# **CURRICULUM VITAE**

Name: dr. Jantsje M. Mol Date of birth: 17-08-1990

Address: E7.30, Roetersstraat 11, 1018 WB Amsterdam

E-mail: j.m.mol@uva.nl
Website: www.jantsje.nl



I am a postdoctoral researcher at CREED, the Center for Research in Experimental Economics and political Decision making of the University of Amsterdam and a Research Fellow at Tinbergen. My main interests are experimental economics and behavioral economics. Currently, I am working on a project studying the importance of trust in the sharing economy.

I have a research master in neuroeconomics from Maastricht University and a PhD in behavioral economics from Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam. My PhD thesis entitled *Improving flood preparedness using insights from economic experiments* can be found here.

# **PUBLICATIONS**

- Mol, J. M., Botzen, W. J. W., & Blasch, J. E. (2022). After the virtual flood: Risk perceptions and flood preparedness after virtual reality risk communication. *Judgment and Decision Making*, 17(1), 189–214. <a href="https://sidm.org/journal/20/200909/jdm200909.pdf">https://sidm.org/journal/20/200909/jdm200909.pdf</a>
- Botzen, W. J. W., **Mol, J. M**., Robinson, P. J., Zhang, J., & Czajkowski, J. (2021). Individual hurricane evacuation intentions during the COVID-19 pandemic: insights for risk communication and emergency management policies. *Natural Hazards*, 0123456789. https://doi.org/10.1007/s11069-021-05064-2
- Shalvi, S., Mol, J. M., Molho, C., Vu, L., Leib, M., & Soraperra, I. (2021). Psychological Science for a Responsible Sharing Economy. *Current Opinion in Psychology*. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.copsyc.2021.08.032">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.copsyc.2021.08.032</a>
- **Mol, J. M**., Botzen, W. J. W., Blasch, J. E., Kranzler, E. C., and Kunreuther, H. C. (2021). All by myself? Testing descriptive social norm-nudges to increase flood preparedness among homeowners. *Behavioural Public Policy*. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/bpp.2021.17">https://doi.org/10.1017/bpp.2021.17</a>
- Morren\*, M., **Mol\*, J. M.**, Blasch, J. E., & Malek, Ž. (2021). Changing diets Testing the impact of knowledge and information nudges on sustainable dietary choices. Journal of *Environmental Psychology*, 75, 101610. \*shared first authorship https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jenvp.2021.101610
- Bloemendaal, N., de Moel, H., **Mol, J. M**., Bosma, P. R. M., Polen, A. N., & Collins, J. M. (2021). Adequately reflecting the severity of tropical cyclones using the new Tropical Cyclone Severity Scale. *Environmental Research Letters*, *16*(1), 014048. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/abd131">https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/abd131</a>
- Mol, J.M., Botzen, W.J.W., Blasch, J.E., (2020). Behavioral motivations for self-insurance under different disaster risk insurance schemes. *Journal of Economic Behavior and Organization*, 180, 967-991, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.jebo.2018.12.007
- Mol, J. M., Botzen, W. J. W., Blasch, J. E., and de Moel, H. (2020). Insights into flood risk misperceptions of homeowners in the Dutch river delta. *Risk Analysis*. https://doi.org/10.1111/risa.13479
- **Mol, J.M.**, van der Heijden, E.C.M., Potters, J.J.M., (2020). (Not) alone in the world: Cheating in the presence of a virtual observer. *Experimental Economics*. https://doi.org/10.1007/s10683-020-09644-0
- Mol, J. M., Botzen, W. J. W., and Blasch, J. E. (2020). Risk reduction in compulsory disaster insurance: Experimental evidence on moral hazard and financial incentives. *Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Economics, 84 (February 2020), 101500*<a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socec.2019.101500">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socec.2019.101500</a>
- **Mol, J.M.**, (2019). Goggles in the lab: Economic experiments in immersive virtual environments. *Journal of Behavioral and Experimental Economics*, 79(C), 155-164. <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socec.2019.02.007">https://doi.org/10.1016/j.socec.2019.02.007</a>

### **EDUCATION**

2016 – 2021 PhD in behavioral economics of natural disaster risk

Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Institute for Environmental Studies, department of Environmental Economics

Research visit Risk Management and Decision Processes Center, Wharton School, University of Pennsylvania

2014 – 2016 Master of Science in Cognitive & Clinical Neuroscience (Research Master)

Maastricht University

Track: Neuroeconomics.

Internship: Economic Experiments in Virtual Reality, Tilburg University, grade 9/10

**2011 – 2014 Bachelor of Science** 

Tilburg University

Liberal Arts & Sciences. Major: Social Sciences. Graduated cum laude. Semester abroad at Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

Coordinator & lecturer

2022 Climate Change Economics (MSc), University of Amsterdam

Lecturer

2019-2021 Guest lecture on Experimental Economics, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

2017-2018 oTree Workshop for PhDs and Faculty, Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam, Tilburg University

**Teaching Assistant** 

2016 – 2020 Environmental Economics (MSc), Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

2018 – 2020 Statistics in R (MSc), Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Theses supervision

2021 - present University of Amsterdam: MSc. Economics & Business (7)

2018- 2020 Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam: MSc. Environmental Resource Management (2)

BSc. Earth & Economics (1)

## SELECTED SEMINAR AND CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS

2021 - SPUDM 2021 (online)

ESA 2021 Global Around-The-Clock-Meetings (online)

2020 - ESA 2020 Global Around-The-Clock-Meetings (online)

- SABE 2020 (online)

- BIT (behavioral insights team) webinar (invited)

(for policy makers at the Ministry of Infrastructure and Water Management)

2019 - Norms and Behavioral Change Workshop, University of Pennsylvania (poster)

SPUDM, Amsterdam (poster) – Runner up Best Poster Award

- European conference on risk perception, Université de Cergy Pontoise, Paris (invited)

2018 - CEAR/MRIC Behavioral Insurance Workshop, Munich

BEEC, Universidad del Rosario, Bogotá (poster)

2017 - VR for experimental economics workshop, RWTH Aachen (invited)

- TIBER Symposium, Tilburg University

# **SKILLS**

**Languages**: Dutch: native

English: fluent

German, Spanish, French: basic

Software skills: R, Stata, SPSS, Microsoft Office, oTree, Adobe Creative Suite: advanced

MATLAB, HTML, Django, Python, JavaScript, ArcGIS Pro: intermediate